<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Mystical Tattoos</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="tattoos.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Rinxin/elements/master/core/information/tattoos.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>


	<element name="Tome of Mystical Tattoos" type="Information" source="Tome of Mystical Tattoos" id="ID_NATWUNS_TOMT_INFORMATION_TOME_OF_MYSTICAL_TATTOOS">
        <description>
        <h3>MAGIC TATTOOS</h3>
        <p>Mystical tattoos are an ancient form of magic that imparts bearers with extraordinary gifts. They can be seen on any creature willing to allow magic to be embedded deeper into their being than ever before.</p>
        <p class="indent">A tattoo’s magical properties are born of their magically imbued designs, often a testament to the original tattooist’s expertise. A great example of this is a special variant of magic tattoos known as spellbangers, smaller designs replicating arcane spellcasting, restricted to the same tattooist that created them.</p>
        <p class="indent">Magic tattoos are imbued with power by their creators. While sketching, tattooists weave their magics directly into the ink of their design. The design is layered with intent, serving as both pathway and instructions for the tattooist’s magic. This can be an impossible task for those inexperienced in the tattooists’ method. In a process that takes just a few seconds after the design’s completion, the magic blooms within the design, and it acquires its intended effect or property.</p>
        <h4>ALTERNATIVE TATTOO SYSTEM</h4>
        <p>The practice adopted by tattooists for distributing their magic tattoos is simple and permits them to benefit from their work, while still allowing for tattoos to be widely accessible. Magic tattoos are initially sketched within the pages of an enchanted sketchbook by a tattooist. After the design is drawn on an enchanted sketchbook page, any individual may extract that tattoo into an empty needle using tattooist’s tools. This allows designs to be more easily distributed or acquired. The page is empty once the design is extracted, but a special needle is now ready to be applied.</p>
        <p class="indent">The creator’s whims often drive the initial design, but this can be steered by other individuals requiring a particular result. Some would say that this is what sets magic tattoos apart from other magic items. The degree of control that tattooists have over their designs while applying their artistry and magics often yields truly remarkable results, limited only by their skill and imagination.</p>

        <h4>TATTOOIST’S TOOLS</h4>
        <p>The tattooist’s tools are a type of artisan’s tools consisting of two main components - the hammer and chisel. The chisel contains a simple mechanism that can twist to clasp onto needles of various widths. The hammer can act as an activator when it strikes the chisel, temporarily applying a magnetic property unique to magically-imbued inks into the needle.</p>
        <p class="indent">One of the main uses of tattooist’s tools in regards to magic tattoos is extraction. An individual holds the chisel affixed with an empty needle against an enchanted sketchbook page or skin upon which a magic tattoo is applied. The wielder then taps the opposite end of the chisel, drawing the tattoo design inside of the affixed, empty needle.</p>
        <p class="indent">The tattooist’s tools also include plenty of needles and medical supplies for sterilization. This is necessary in case the tattooist’s tools are used to apply mundane tattoos as well. For non-magical tattoo applications, the chisel’s needle can be dipped into the appropriate pigments and then hammered against an individual’s skin, scales, or feathers to ink a tattoo.</p>

        <h4>APPLICATION & ATTUNEMENT</h4>
        <p>Applying a magic tattoo from a needle simply requires that the special needle be held against one’s skin. A magic tattoo counts towards the number of magic items to which a creature can attune.</p>
        <p class="indent">The design slowly flows from the needle into the skin upon contact, molding itself to suit the individual’s body. An applied tattoo appears as it did on its sketchbook page, retaining the visual properties of the ink used when it was sketched. In this way, the design transitions from page to person through a needle.</p>
        <p class="indent">For unusual skin types, the tattoo will often take on a different form. As an example, a creature covered in fur or feathers might witness the tattoo take shape as markings as it leaves the needle. A creature with a metallic exterior might see the tattoo engrave itself onto their shell. As a tattoo is simply another form of magic item, this can be interpreted as the attunement process.</p>
        <p class="indent">The process to end attunement to a magic tattoo is different from the process to end attunement to a normal magic item. A creature other than the one to whom the tattoo is applied must use tattooist’s tools and an empty needle to extract the tattoo from the skin, as it was once extracted from a tattooist’s sketchbook page.</p>
        <h4>BIGGER ISN’T ALWAYS BETTER</h4>
        <p>While there is undoubtedly more beauty to admire in tattoos of increasing size and complexity, these factors often belie their true potential.</p>
        <p class="indent">A more pertinent factor to investigate when shopping for a new tattoo is the original intent behind its design and, of course, aesthetics. These factors will determine whether the tattoo suits its future bearer and whether the tattoo will work in harmony with their existing abilities. You will find that tattoos ranging drastically in rarity and power can be of the same proportion.</p>
        <p class="indent">Also of note, magic tattoos that are applied on the same body part can coexist. All magic tattoos can be layered upon each other, with individuals not having to fear for their properties being tainted or diminished. Magic tattoos are sketched with purpose, and are not so easily disrupted simply by their proximity to one other. In this case, an individual can mentally decide which tattoo sits at the forefront to make it so.</p>
        <h4>PAIN & DISMEMBERMENT</h4>
        <p>Although magic tattoos should initially be applied to a specific body part, the magic connects more intimately with the host as time progresses. In the event a tattoo is damaged or a body part lost, the tattoo retains its magical properties and will immediately shift to the next most appropriate part of the attuned individual’s body (GM’s choice).</p>

        <h3>THE TATTOO PARLOR</h3>
        <p>Stepping into your first tattoo parlor can be an overwhelming experience. You will find enchanted sketchbook pages plastered on the walls, showcasing the sitting tattoo artist’s work, as well those of their colleagues. Tattooist’s tools, from the basic copper to gold-plated, will be available for purchase, often along with a plethora of swirling, colorful, and iridescent inks lining the shelves.</p>
        <p class="indent">Tattooists use ink as they sketch a tattoo and anyone may use inks later on to alter a tattoo. While a finished tattoo is extracted into a needle, it can be dipped using a set of tattooist’s tools into a bottle of ink to absorb the ink and the requisite volume. This completely replaces the visual property of any existing ink used to create or alter the tattoo at an earlier point in time. Each 1-ounce bottle contains enough ink to create one chest or back tattoo, or two face, neck, arm, or leg tattoos.</p>

            <table>
                <th><tr><td>Name</td><td>Cost</td></tr></th>
                <tr><td>Hammer</td><td>15gp</tr>
                <tr><td>Chisel</td><td>15gp
                <tr><td>Medical Supplies</td><td>10gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Tattoo Needles (100)</td><td>1gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Enchanted Sketchbook</td><td>50gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Base Ink</td><td>10gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Colored Ink</td><td>20gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Dancing Ink</td><td>30gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Glowing Ink </td><td>80gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Hell's Ink</td><td>90gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Invisible Ink</td><td>50gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Mood Ink</td><td>100gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Reflective Ink</td><td>50gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Regulating Ink</td><td>25gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Stardust Ink</td><td>100gp</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>Magic Tatto Price Guide</h5>
            <table>
                <th><tr><td>Rarity</td><td>Face, Neck, Arm & Leg Tattoos Asking Price</td><td>Average</td><td>Chest & Back Tattoo Asking Price</td><td>Average</td></tr></th>
                <tr><td>Common</td><td>1d4 x 10gp</td><td>25gp</td><td>(1d4+1) x 10gp</td><td>35gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Uncommon</td><td>1d4 x 100gp</td><td>250gp</td><td>(1d4+1) x 100gp</td><td>350gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Rare</td><td>1d6 x 1000gp</td><td>3500gp</td><td>(1d6+2) x 1000gp</td><td>5500gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Very Rare</td><td>1d8 x 10,000gp</td><td>45,000gp</td><td>(1d8+2) x 10,000gp</td><td>65,000gp</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Legendary</td><td>1d12 x 25,000gp</td><td>162,500gp</td><td>(1d12+2) x 25,000gp</td><td>212,500gp</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p><b>Karl’s Notes:</b> You can choose to simply use the tattoo prices listed under the “Face, Neck, Arm & Leg Tattoos” columns for all tattoos. The distinction here exists in case you wish to account for the increased time and labor involved when a tattoo artist creates a larger tattoo design such as those which are to be applied on the chest or back.</p>
            <h4>TATTOO PRICING</h4>
            <p>As one might imagine, each tattoo is unique and valued differently based on factors ranging from its functionality to its visual appeal. This can lead to some fluctuations in terms of pricing.</p>
            <p class="indent">One thing that remains constant is each tattooist’s knowledge of tattoo rarity, as rarity is tied to how difficult it was for them to gather the right components to sketch the tattoo in the first place. As a result, it is the most accurate determinant of tattoo price. Tattooists will often price within the range provided in the Magic Tattoos Price Guide table on the previous page, unless there are exceptional circumstances. As magic tattoos do not fade over time—whether in terms of power or appearance—their value does not fluctuate as they age.</p>
            <p class="indent">Another determining factor in pricing is the dimensions of the tattoo. It undeniably takes more time and effort to craft a larger tattoo, resulting in a slight bump in prices when it comes to purchasing tattoos that are to be applied on one’s chest or back. However, as a tattoo’s power and function do not correlate with its size, it often becomes a point of contention during sales. Less experienced tattooists have been haggled down on this point, being more artists than salespeople.</p>

            <h4>TATTOO AVAILABILITY</h4>
            <p>Another factor to keep in mind when browsing for magic tattoos is that the availability of certain designs will always be a complicated matter. Any tattooist will only be an expert in crafting a particular set of tattoo designs, and their stock will always reflect this.</p>
            <p class="indent">A practice many tattooists have adopted is trading wares among their shops. This allows for much more variety in merchandise within each establishment. A side effect of this is that you will still see many of the same tattoo designs if you are only visiting parlors within the same region. It is best to travel out of the area if your goal is to procure a wide and varied selection of mystical tattoos.</p>
        </description>
    </element>
</elements>