<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Deep Magic: Collection</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="05-ley-lines.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/third-party/kobold-press/deep-magic/05-ley-lines.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>


	<element name="Using Ley Lines" type="Information" source="Deep Magic 05: Ley Lines" id="ID_KBP_DMLL_INFORMATION_USING_LEY_LINES">
		<description>
			<p>Spellcasters can tap ley lines to fill their spells with sudden bursts of power. While this can be dangerous, a skilled caster can create fantastic effects with extra power.</p>
			<p class="indent">Ley lines vary in intensity from weak trickles to titanic torrents of mystical power. In general, the more intense the ley line, the more potent its effect on magic and the more difficult it is to tap into.</p>
			<p class="indent">They are also classified as either unlocked or locked. These two categories are subjective; a ley line is locked only to individual spellcasters who’ve locked it, while it remains unlocked to all others. Locked ley lines produce predictable, repeatable benefits when worked into magic. Unlocked ley lines are no more difficult to tap into than locked ones (of the same intensity), but they are unpredictable and dangerous to use. They also bleed magical energy into the surrounding environment, which sometimes causes strange, unnatural effects in the neighborhood.</p>
			<p class="indent">To tap the potential of a ley line requires specialized knowledge, represented by either the Ley Initiate feat or the Geomancy arcane tradition. If your game doesn’t utilize optional feats, you can instead allow a spellcaster who has a geomancer tutor or who has access to ample research material to learn the technique for tapping ley lines via training as a downtime activity.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once a spellcaster understands how to access the energy of a ley line, the procedure is straightforward. When a spell is cast within 30 feet of a ley line, the spellcaster can tap the line’s power to augment his or her magic. This requires a successful ability check using the caster’s spellcasting ability but without including any proficiency bonus. The DC of the check equals 10 + the level of the spell being cast. A successful check harnesses the power of the ley line, and the spell is modified according to the line’s intensity (weak, strong, or titanic). If the check fails but the result is within 4 of the DC, the spell is cast normally with no bonus effect and no penalty. If the check fails by 5 or more, the spell is cast normally but the spellcaster suffers backlash (see below).</p>
			<p class="indent">When a ley line is tapped successfully, the effect depends on whether the line is locked or unlocked. A locked ley line always has the same effect for the spellcaster who locked it. An unlocked ley line is unpredictable; every time it’s tapped, the player rolls 1d10 and consults the table corresponding to the ley line’s intensity (weak, strong, or titanic).</p>
			<h5 class="caption">WEAK LEY LINE EFFECTS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>If your spell attack misses or if the target makes a successful saving throw, you can choose a new target within 10 feet of the original target and within range. Make a new attack roll with disadvantage, or the new target makes a saving throw with advantage.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You can delay the effect of your spell for up to 5 rounds. Choose how many rounds you want the spell to delay at the moment it’s cast. The spell takes effect at the start of your turn that many rounds later. All parameters regarding the spell’s targeting, area, color, etc., must be set when the spell is cast, not when it takes effect.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>If your spell deals acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can change the damage to one of the other listed types.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>If your spell affects multiple creatures, choose one. That creature has disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against the spell.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Double the range of your spell.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>A creature that takes cold damage from your spell is restrained until the end of its next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Creatures damaged by your spell are also deafened for 1 minute. A deafened creature makes a Constitution saving throw at the end of its turn to end the deafness effect.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Cast your spell without verbal components.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>A creature damaged by your spell is also knocked prone unless it makes a successful Strength saving throw.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>Roll twice on this table (treat duplicate results as “no additional effect”), or roll once on the Strong Ley Line Effects table.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5 class="caption">STRONG LEY LINE EFFECTS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>You can reroll a number of damage dice up to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 1).</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Treat your spell as if it were cast with a spell slot one level higher.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Creatures damaged by your spell are also poisoned for 1 minute. A poisoned creature makes a Constitution saving throw at the end of its turn to end the poisoning effect.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>You regain 1d6 hit points per level of the spell.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Your spell ignores damage resistance.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>A creature that takes acid or fire damage from your spell takes an additional 3d6 damage of the same type at the start of its next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Targets of your spell have disadvantage on their saving throws against it.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>You can choose to exclude any creature you can see from the area of your spell.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>If your spell has a range of self, you can cast it as a touch spell instead.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>Roll twice on this table (treat duplicate results as “no additional effect”), or roll once on the Titanic Ley Line Effects table.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5 class="caption">TITANIC LEY LINE EFFECTS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>If your spell affects only one target, it instead affects up to six targets of your choice.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>If your spell affects an area, double the area’s size.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Creatures affected by your spell are incapacitated for 1 minute. An incapacitated creature makes a Wisdom saving throw at the end of its turn to end the incapacitation effect.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>You gain a +5 bonus to your AC until the start of your next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Casting your spell this turn uses only a bonus action; you still have an action to use.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Creatures immune to the damage of your spell take half damage instead.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Treat your spell as if it were cast with a spell slot two levels higher.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Concentration on your spell can’t be broken by damage.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>A creature damaged by your spell is pushed 10 feet away from you and knocked prone. Its speed is reduced to 0 until it makes a successful Constitution saving throw at the start of its turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>Choose one effect listed above.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5 class="caption">LEY LINE BACKLASH</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>The spell produces only a harmless display of bright color and loud noise.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You are incapacitated until the end of your next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>You fall unconscious for 1 minute. You awake if you take damage or if another creature uses an action to shake you awake.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>The next spell you cast fails, and the spell slot is wasted.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Targets have advantage on saving throws against your spells for 1 hour.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>For 1 hour, you must make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw every time you cast a spell. If the saving throw fails, the spell fails and the spell slot is wasted.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>You take 2d6 force damage per level of the spell that caused the backlash (cantrips cause 1d6 damage).</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>You lose one spell slot of your highest available level, and all charged magic items in your possession lose 1d4 charges.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>Your spell fails, and you unleash a random burst of magic as if you’d used a wand of wonder.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>You lose all your remaining spell slots, the ley line disappears for 24 hours, and all charged magic items in your possession fully recharge. You must make a successful DC 20 Charisma saving throw or fall unconscious; you awaken after 1 hour, if you take damage, or if another creature uses an action to shake you awake.</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
	</element>
</elements>
