<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Items</name>
		<description>The World of Morad Campagin Setting.</description>
		<author url="">Richard Mraz</author>
		<update version="0.1">
			<file name="01-common.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Rinxin/elements/master/core/items/01-common.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
<!--Wondrous Item-->
	<!--A-->
		<element name="Alchemist's Medicine Maker" type="Magic Item" source="Relics of the Realms - Volume 5" id="ID_BONUSACTION_ROTR5_MAGIC_ITEM_ALCHEMISTS_MEDICINE_MAKER">
			<description>
				<p><b>Cure-all Potion. </b>You can fill this flask with any type of liquid that is not poisonous. After 24 hours have passed the liquid becomes imbued with the enchantment. You can use a bonus action to speak a command word which causes the imbued liquid to gain or switch properties. The liquid takes on the properties of one the potions or spells from the table below. The liquid loses the properties if left out of this flask for over a minute.</p>
				<table>
				<h5>Potion Properties</h5>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Option</td><td>Origin Type</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Freedom of Movement</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Greater Restoration</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Lesser Restoration</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Potion of Healing, Greater</td><td>Potion</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Potion of Heroism</td><td>Potion</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Potion of Resistance, Poison</td><td>Potion</td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="enhancement"></set>
				<set name="slot"></set>
				<set name="attunement" addition=""></set>
				<set name="weapon"></set>
				<set name="armor"></set>
				<set name="name-format"></set>
				<set name="stackable"></set>
				<set name="charges"></set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Amulet of Health" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_HEALTH">
			<description>
				<p>Your Constitution score is 19 while you wear this amulet. It has no effect on you if your Constitution is 19 or higher without it.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">constitution</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">neck</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<stat name="constitution:score:set" value="19" bonus="base" />
			</rules>
		</element>
	<!--B-->
		<element name="Bag of Beans" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BAG_OF_BEANS">
			<description>
				<p>Inside this heavy cloth bag are 3d4 dry beans. The bag weighs ½ pound plus 1/4 pound for each bean it contains.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you dump the bag's contents out on the ground, they explode in a 10-foot radius, extending from the beans. Each creature in the area, including you, must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 5d4 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The fire ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you remove a bean from the bag, plant it in dirt or sand, and then water it, the bean produces an effect 1 minute later from the ground where it was planted. The GM can choose an effect from the following table, determine it randomly, or create an effect.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>d100</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<tr><td>01</td><td>5d4 toadstools sprout. If a creature eats a toadstool, roll any die. On an odd roll, the eater must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or take 5d6 poison damage and become poisoned for 1 hour. On an even roll, the eater gains 5d6 temporary hit points for 1 hour.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>02-10</td><td>A geyser erupts and spouts water, beer, berry juice, tea, vinegar, wine, or oil (GM's choice) 30 feet into the air for 1d12 rounds.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>11-20</td><td>A treant sprouts. There's a 50 percent chance that the treant is chaotic evil and attacks.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>21-30</td><td>An animate, immobile stone statue in your likeness rises. It makes verbal threats against you. If you leave it and others come near, it describes you as the most heinous of villains and directs the newcomers to find and attack you. If you are on the same plane of existence as the statue, it knows where you are. The statue becomes inanimate after 24 hours.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>31-40</td><td>A campfire with blue flames springs forth and burns for 24 hours (or until it is extinguished).</td></tr>
						<tr><td>41-50</td><td>1d6 + 6 shriekers sprout</td></tr>
						<tr><td>51-60</td><td>1d4 + 8 bright pink toads crawl forth. Whenever a toad is touched, it transforms into a Large or smaller monster of the GM's choice. The monster remains for 1 minute, then disappears in a puff of bright pink smoke.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>61-70</td><td>A hungry bulette burrows up and attacks.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>71-80</td><td>A fruit tree grows. It has 1d10 + 20 fruit, 1d8 of which act as randomly determined magic potions, while one acts as an ingested poison of the GM's choice. The tree vanishes after 1 hour. Picked fruit remains, retaining any magic for 30 days.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>81-90</td><td>A nest of 1d4 + 3 eggs springs up. Any creature that eats an egg must make a DC 20 Constitution saving throw. On a successful save, a creature permanently increases its lowest ability score by 1, randomly choosing among equally low scores. On a failed save, the creature takes 10d6 force damage from an internal magical explosion.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>91-99</td><td>A pyramid with a 60-foot-square base bursts upward. Inside is a sarcophagus containing a mummy lord. The pyramid is treated as the mummy lord's lair, and its sarcophagus contains treasure of the GM's choice.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>00</td><td>A giant beanstalk sprouts, growing to a height of the GM's choice. The top leads where the GM chooses, such as to a great view, a cloud giant's castle, or a different plane of existence.</td></tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Bead of Force" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BEAD_OF_FORCE">
			<description>
				<p>This small black sphere measures 3/4 of an inch in diameter and weighs an ounce. Typically, 1d4 + 4 <em>beads of force</em> are found together.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can use an action to throw the bead up to 60 feet. The bead explodes on impact and is destroyed. Each creature within a 10-foot radius of where the bead landed must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or take 5d4 force damage. A sphere of transparent force then encloses the area for 1 minute. Any creature that failed the save and is completely within the area is trapped inside this sphere. Creatures that succeeded on the save, or are partially within the area, are pushed away from the center of the sphere until they are no longer inside it. Only breathable air can pass through the sphere's wall. No attack or other effect can.</p>
				<p class="indent">An enclosed creature can use its action to push against the sphere's wall, moving the sphere up to half the creature's walking speed. The sphere can be picked up, and its magic causes it to weigh only 1 pound, regardless of the weight of creatures inside.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Belt of Dwarvenkind" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_DWARVENKIND">
			<description>
				<p>While wearing this belt, you gain the following benefits:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>Your Constitution score increases by 2, to a maximum of 20.</li>
					<li>You have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to interact with dwarves.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>In addition, while attuned to the belt, you have a 50 percent chance each day at dawn of growing a full beard if you're capable of growing one, or a visibly thicker beard if you already have one.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you aren't a dwarf, you gain the following additional benefits while wearing the belt:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</li>
					<li>You have darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.</li>
					<li>You can speak, read, and write Dwarvish.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">constitution, persuasion</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">waist</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<stat name="constitution" value="2" />
				<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" requirements="!ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF" />
				<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" requirements="!ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF" />
				<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DWARVISH" requirements="!ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Belt of Hill Giant Strength" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_HILL_GIANT_STRENGTH">
			<description>
				<p>While wearing this belt, your Strength score changes to a score granted by the belt. The item has no effect on you if your Strength without the belt is equal to or greater than the belt’s score.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">strength</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">waist</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<stat name="strength:score:set" value="21" bonus="base" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Boots of Levitation" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BOOTS_OF_LEVITATION">
			<description>
				<p>While you wear these boots, you can use an action to cast the <em>levitate</em> spell on yourself at will.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">feet</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Boots of Speed" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BOOTS_OF_SPEED">
			<description>
				<p>While you wear these boots, you can use a bonus action and click the boots' heels together. If you do, the boots double your walking speed, and any creature that makes an opportunity attack against you has disadvantage on the attack roll. If you click your heels together again, you end the effect.</p>
				<p>When the boots' property has been used for a total of 10 minutes, the magic ceases to function until you finish a long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">feet</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Bowl of Commanding Water Elementals" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BOWL_OF_COMMANDING_WATER_ELEMENTALS">
			<description>
				<p>While this bowl is filled with water, you can use an action to speak the bowl's command word and summon a water elemental, as if you had cast the <em>conjure elemental</em> spell. The bowl can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</p>
				<p class="indent">The bowl is about 1 foot in diameter and half as deep. It weighs 3 pounds and holds about 3 gallons.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">summon</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Bracers of Defense" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BRACERS_OF_DEFENSE">
			<description>
				<p>While wearing these bracers, you gain a +2 bonus to AC if you are wearing no armor and using no shield.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">armor</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">arms</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<stat name="ac:misc" value="2" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Brazier of Commanding Fire Elementals" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BRAZIER_OF_COMMANDING_FIRE_ELEMENTALS">
			<description>
				<p>While a fire burns in this brass brazier, you can use an action to speak the brazier's command word and summon a fire elemental, as if you had cast the <em>conjure elemental</em> spell. The brazier can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</p>
				<p class="indent">The brazier weighs 5 pounds.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">summon</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Butcher’s Bib" type="Magic Item" source="Explorer’s Guide to Wildemount" id="ID_WOTC_EGTW_MAGIC_ITEM_BUTCHERS_BIB">
			<description>
				<p>This black leather apron is perpetually covered by blood, even after being washed off. You gain the following benefits while wearing the apron:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>Once per turn when you roll damage for a melee attack with a weapon, you can reroll the weapon’s damage dice. If you do so, you must use the second total.</li>
					<li>Your weapon attacks that deal slashing damage score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="slot">misc</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--C-->
		<element name="Cape of the Mountebank" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_CAPE_OF_THE_MOUNTEBANK">
			<description>
				<p>This cape smells faintly of brimstone. While wearing it, you can use it to cast the <em>dimension door</em> spell as an action. This property of the cape can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you disappear, you leave behind a cloud of smoke, and you appear in a similar cloud of smoke at your destination. The smoke lightly obscures the space you left and the space you appear in, and it dissipates at the end of your next turn. A light or stronger wind disperses the smoke.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">teleport</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Censer of Controlling Air Elementals" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_CENSER_OF_CONTROLLING_AIR_ELEMENTALS">
			<description>
				<p>While incense is burning in this censer, you can use an action to speak the censer's command word and summon an air elemental, as if you had cast the <em>conjure elemental</em> spell. The censer can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</p>
				<p class="indent">This 6-inch-wide, 1-foot-high vessel resembles a chalice with a decorated lid. It weighs 1 pound.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">summon</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Chime of Opening" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_CHIME_OF_OPENING">
			<description>
				<p>This hollow metal tube measures about 1 foot long and weighs 1 pound. You can strike it as an action, pointing it at an object within 120 feet of you that can be opened, such as a door, lid, or lock. The chime issues a clear tone, and one lock or latch on the object opens unless the sound can't reach the object. If no locks or latches remain, the object itself opens.</p>
				<p class="indent">The chime can be used ten times. After the tenth time, it cracks and becomes useless.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Cloak of Displacement" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOAK_OF_DISPLACEMENT">
			<description>
				<p>While you wear this cloak, it projects an illusion that makes you appear to be standing in a place near your actual location, causing any creature to have disadvantage on attack rolls against you. If you take damage, the property ceases to function until the start of your next turn. This property is suppressed while you are incapacitated, restrained, or otherwise unable to move.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Cloak of the Bat" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOAK_OF_THE_BAT">
			<description>
				<p>While wearing this cloak, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. In an area of dim light or darkness, you can grip the edges of the cloak with both hands and use it to fly at a speed of 40 feet. If you ever fail to grip the cloak's edges while flying in this way, or if you are no longer in dim light or darkness, you lose this flying speed.</p>
				<p class="indent">While wearing the cloak in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to cast <em>polymorph</em> on yourself, transforming into a bat.  While you are in the form of the bat, you retain your Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. The cloak can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">stealth, fly</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Cube of Force" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_CUBE_OF_FORCE">
			<description>
				<p>This cube is about an inch across. Each face has a distinct marking on it that can be pressed. The cube starts with 36 charges, and it regains 1d20 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can use an action to press one of the cube's faces, expending a number of charges based on the chosen face, as shown in the Cube of Force Faces table. Each face has a different effect. If the cube has insufficient charges remaining, nothing happens. Otherwise, a barrier of invisible force springs into existence, forming a cube 15 feet on a side. The barrier is centered on you, moves with you, and lasts for 1 minute, until you use an action to press the cube's sixth face, or the cube runs out of charges. You can change the barrier's effect by pressing a different face of the cube and expending the requisite number of charges, resetting the duration.</p>
				<p class="indent">If your movement causes the barrier to come into contact with a solid object that can't pass through the cube, you can't move any closer to that object as long as the barrier remains.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Face</td><td>Charges</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<tr><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>Gases, wind, and fog can't pass through the barrier.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>Nonliving matter can't pass through the barrier. Walls, floors, and ceilings can pass through at your discretion.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>Living matter can't pass through the barrier.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>Spell effects can't pass through the barrier.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>Nothing can pass through the barrier. Walls, floors, and ceilings can pass through at your discretion.</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6</td><td>0</td><td>The barrier deactivates.</td></tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
				<p>The cube loses charges when the barrier is targeted by certain spells or comes into contact with certain spell or magic item effects, as shown in the table below.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Spell or Item</td><td>Charges Lost</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<tr><td><em>Disintegrate</em></td><td>1d12</td></tr>
						<tr><td><em>Horn of blasting</em></td><td>1d10</td></tr>
						<tr><td><em>Passwall</em></td><td>1d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td><em>Prismatic spray</em></td><td>1d20</td></tr>
						<tr><td><em>Wall of fire</em></td><td>1d4</td></tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="charges">36</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--D-->
		<element name="Daern’s Instant Fortress" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_DAERNS_INSTANT_FORTRESS">
			<description>
				<p>You can use an action to place this 1-inch metal cube on the ground and speak its command word. The cube rapidly grows into a fortress that remains until you use an action to speak the command word that dismisses it, which works only if the fortress is empty.</p>
				<p class="indent">The fortress is a square tower, 20 feet on a side and 30 feet high, with arrow slits on all sides and a battlement atop it. Its interior is divided into two floors, with a ladder running along one wall to connect them. The ladder ends at a trapdoor leading to the roof. When activated, the tower has a small door on the side facing you. The door opens only at your command, which you can speak as a bonus action. It is immune to the <em>knock</em> spell and similar magic, such as that of a <em>chime of opening</em>.</p>
				<p class="indent">Each creature in the area where the fortress appears must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 10d10 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. In either case, the creature is pushed to an unoccupied space outside but next to the fortress. Objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried take this damage and are pushed automatically.</p>
				<p class="indent">The tower is made of adamantine, and its magic prevents it from being tipped over. The roof, the door, and the walls each have 100 hit points, immunity to damage from nonmagical weapons excluding siege weapons, and resistance to all other damage. Only a <em>wish</em> spell can repair the fortress (this use of the spell counts as replicating a spell of 8th level or lower). Each casting of <em>wish</em> causes the roof, the door, or one wall to regain 50 hit points.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Dimensional Shackles" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_DIMENSIONAL_SHACKLES">
			<description>
				<p>You can use an action to place these shackles on an incapacitated creature. The shackles adjust to fit a creature of Small to Large size. In addition to serving as mundane manacles, the shackles prevent a creature bound by them from using any method of extradimensional movement, including teleportation or travel to a different plane of existence. They don't prevent the creature from passing through an interdimensional portal.</p>
				<p class="indent">You and any creature you designate when you use the shackles can use an action to remove them. Once every 30 days, the bound creature can make a DC 30 Strength (Athletics) check. On a success, the creature breaks free and destroys the shackles.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Docent" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_DOCENT">
			<description>
				<p>A docent is a small metal sphere, about 2 inches across, studded with dragonshards. To attune to a docent, you must embed the item somewhere on your body, such as your chest or your eye socket.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> A docent is a sentient item of any alignment with an Intelligence of 16, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 14. It perceives the world through your senses. It communicates telepathically with you and can speak, read, and understand any language it knows (see "Random Properties" below).</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Life Support.</em></strong> Whenever you end your turn with 0 hit points, the docent can make a Wisdom (Medicine) check with a +6 bonus. If this check succeeds, the docent stabilizes you.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> A docent has the following properties:</p>
				<ul class="unstyled">
					<li><strong>Languages.</strong> The docent knows Common, Giant, and 1d4 additional languages chosen by the DM. If a docent knows fewer than six languages, it can learn a new language after it hears or reads the language through your senses.</li>
					<li><strong>Skills.</strong> The docent has a +7 bonus to one of the following skills (roll a d4): (1) Arcana, (2) History, (3) Investigation, or (4) Nature.</li>
					<li><strong>Spells.</strong> The docent knows one of the following spells and can cast it at will, requiring no components (roll a d6): (1-2) detect evil and good or (3-6) detect magic. The docent decides when to cast the spell.</li>
				</ul>
				<br/>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> A docent is designed to advise and assist the warforged it’s attached to. One of the simple functions of a docent is to serve as a translator. The docent’s properties are under its control, and if you have a bad relationship with your docent, it might refuse to assist you.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="attunement" addition="by a warforged">true</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--E-->
	<!--F-->
		<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Bronze Griffon" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_BRONZE_GRIFFON">
			<description>
				<p>This bronze statuette is of a griffon rampant. It can become a griffon for up to 6 hours. Once it has been used, it can't be used again until 5 days have passed.</p>
				<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Ebony Fly" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_EBONY_FLY">
			<description>
				<p>This ebony statuette is carved in the likeness of a horsefly. It can become a giant fly for up to 12 hours and can be ridden as a mount. Once it has been used, it can't be used again until 2 days have passed.</p>
				<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Golden Lions" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_GOLDEN_LIONS">
			<description>
				<p>These gold statuettes of lions are always created in pairs. You can use one figurine or both simultaneously. Each can become a lion for up to 1 hour. Once a lion has been used, it can't be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
				<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Ivory Goats" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_IVORY_GOATS">
			<description>
				<p>These ivory statuettes of goats are always created in sets of three. Each goat looks unique and functions differently from the others. Their properties are as follows:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>The <em>goat of traveling</em> can become a Large goat with the same statistics as a riding horse. It has 24 charges, and each hour or portion thereof it spends in beast form costs 1 charge. While it has charges, you can use it as often as you wish. When it runs out of charges, it reverts to a figurine and can't be used again until 7 days have passed, when it regains all its charges.</li>
					<li>The <em>goat of travail</em> becomes a giant goat for up to 3 hours. Once it has been used, it can't be used again until 30 days have passed.</li>
					<li>The <em>goat of terror</em> becomes a giant goat for up to 3 hours. The goat can't attack, but you can remove its horns and use them as weapons. One horn becomes a <em>+1 lance</em>, and the other becomes <em>+2 longsword</em>. Removing a horn requires an action, and the weapons disappear and the horns return when the goat reverts to figurine form.  In addition, the goat radiates a 30-foot-radius aura of terror while you are riding it. Any creature hostile to you that starts its turn in the aura must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of the goat for 1 minute, or until the goat reverts to figurine form.  The frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Once it successfully saves against the effect, a creature is immune to the goat's aura for the next 24 hours. Once the figurine has been used, it can't be used again until 15 days have passed.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="charges">24</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Marble Elephant" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_MARBLE_ELEPHANT">
			<description>
				<p>This marble statuette is about 4 inches high and long. It can become an elephant for up to 24 hours. Once it has been used, it can't be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
				<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Onyx Dog" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_ONYX_DOG">
			<description>
				<p>This onyx statuette of a dog can become a mastiff for up to 6 hours. The mastiff has an Intelligence of 8 and can speak Common. It also has darkvision out to a range of 60 feet and can see invisible creatures and objects within that range. Once it has been used, it can't be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
				<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Serpentine Owl" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_SERPENTINE_OWL">
			<description>
				<p>This serpentine statuette of an owl can become a giant owl for up to 8 hours. Once it has been used, it can't be used again until 2 days have passed. The owl can telepathically communicate with you at any range if you and it are on the same plane of existence.</p>
				<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
				<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>

		<element name="Folding Boat" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FOLDING_BOAT">
			<description>
				<p>This object appears as a wooden box that measures 12 inches long, 6 inches wide, and 6 inches deep. It weighs 4 pounds and floats. It can be opened to store items inside. This item also has three command words, each requiring you to use an action to speak it.</p>
				<p class="indent">One command word causes the box to unfold into a boat 10 feet long, 4 feet wide, and 2 feet deep. The boat has one pair of oars, an anchor, a mast, and a lateen sail. The boat can hold up to four Medium creatures comfortably.</p>
				<p class="indent">The second command word causes the box to unfold into a ship 24 feet long, 8 feet wide, and 6 feet deep. The ship has a deck, rowing seats, five sets of oars, a steering oar, an anchor, a deck cabin, and a mast with a square sail. The ship can hold fifteen Medium creatures comfortably.</p>
				<p class="indent">When the box becomes a vessel, its weight becomes that of a normal vessel its size, and anything that was stored in the box remains in the boat.</p>
				<p class="indent">The third command word causes the <em>folding boat</em> to fold back into a box, provided that no creatures are aboard. Any objects in the vessel that can't fit inside the box remain outside the box as it folds. Any objects in the vessel that can fit inside the box do so.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--G-->
		<element name="Gauntlets of Flaming Fury" type="Magic Item" source="Baldur’s Gate: Descent into Avernus" id="ID_WOCT_BGDIA_MAGIC_ITEM_GAUNTLETS_OF_FLAMING_FURY">
			<description>
				<p>While you wear both these steel gauntlets, any non-magical weapon you grasp with either gauntlet is treated as a magic weapon. As a bonus action, you can use the gauntlets to cause magical flames to envelop one or two melee weapons in your grasp. Each flaming weapon deals and extra 1d6 fire damage on a hit. These flames last until you sheath or let go of either weapon. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">fire</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="slot">hands</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Gem of Seeing" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_GEM_OF_SEEING">
			<description>
				<p>This gem has 3 charges. As an action, you can speak the gem's command word and expend 1 charge. For the next 10 minutes, you have truesight out to 120 feet when you peer through the gem.</p>
				<p class="indent">The gem regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">vision, truesight</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="charges">3</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--H-->
		<element name="Helm of Teleportation" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HELM_OF_TELEPORTATION">
			<description>
				<p>This helm has 3 charges. While wearing it, you can use an action and expend 1 charge to cast the <em>teleport</em> spell from it. The helm regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">teleport</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">head</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="charges">3</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Heward’s Handy Haversack" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HEWARDS_HANDY_HAVERSACK">
			<description>
				<p>This backpack has a central pouch and two side pouches, each of which is an extradimensional space. Each side pouch can hold up to 20 pounds of material, not exceeding a volume of 2 cubic feet. The large central pouch can hold up to 8 cubic feet or 80 pounds of material. The backpack always weighs 5 pounds, regardless of its contents.</p>
				<p class="indent">Placing an object in the haversack follows the normal rules for interacting with objects. Retrieving an item from the haversack requires you to use an action. When you reach into the haversack for a specific item, the item is always magically on top.</p>
				<p class="indent">The haversack has a few limitations. If it is overloaded, or if a sharp object pierces it or tears it, the haversack ruptures and is destroyed. If the haversack is destroyed, its contents are lost forever, although an artifact always turns up again somewhere. If the haversack is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, and the haversack must be put right before it can be used again. If a breathing creature is placed within the haversack, the creature can survive for up to 10 minutes, after which time it begins to suffocate.</p>
				<p class="indent">Placing the haversack inside an extradimensional space created by a <em>bag of holding</em>, <em>portable hole</em>, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it and deposited in a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Horn of Blasting" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HORN_OF_BLASTING">
			<description>
				<p>You can use an action to speak the horn's command word and then blow the horn, which emits a thunderous blast in a 30-foot cone that is audible 600 feet away. Each creature in the cone must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 5d6 thunder damage and is deafened for 1 minute. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and isn't deafened. Creatures and objects made of glass or crystal have disadvantage on the saving throw and take 10d6 thunder damage instead of 5d6.</p>
				<p class="indent">Each use of the horn's magic has a 20 percent chance of causing the horn to explode. The explosion deals 10d6 fire damage to the blower and destroys the horn.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">thunder</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Horn of Valhalla, Brass" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HORN_OF_VALHALLA_BRASS">
			<description>
				<p>You can use an action to blow this horn. In response, warrior spirits from the Valhalla appear within 60 feet of you. They use the statistics of a berserker. They return to Valhalla after 1 hour or when they drop to 0 hit points. Once you use the horn, it can't be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
				<p>Four types of <em>horn of Valhalla</em> are known to exist, each made of a different metal. The horn's type determines how many berserkers answer its summons, as well as the requirement for its use. The GM chooses the horn's type or determines it randomly.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>d100</td><td>Horn Type</td><td>Berserkers Summoned</td><td>Requirement</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<tr><td>01-40</td><td>Silver</td><td>2d4 + 2</td><td>None</td></tr>
						<tr><td>41-75</td><td>Brass</td><td>3d4 + 3</td><td>Proficiency with all simple weapons</td></tr>
						<tr><td>76-90</td><td>Bronze</td><td>4d4 + 4</td><td>Proficiency with all medium armor</td></tr>
						<tr><td>91-00</td><td>Iron</td><td>5d4 + 5</td><td>Proficiency with all martial weapons</td></tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
				<p>If you blow the horn without meeting its requirement, the summoned berserkers attack you. If you meet the requirement, they are friendly to you and your companions and follow your commands.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">summon</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Horn of Valhalla, Silver" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HORN_OF_VALHALLA_SILVER">
			<description>
				<p>You can use an action to blow this horn. In response, warrior spirits from the Valhalla appear within 60 feet of you. They use the statistics of a berserker. They return to Valhalla after 1 hour or when they drop to 0 hit points. Once you use the horn, it can't be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
				<p>Four types of <em>horn of Valhalla</em> are known to exist, each made of a different metal. The horn's type determines how many berserkers answer its summons, as well as the requirement for its use. The GM chooses the horn's type or determines it randomly.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>d100</td><td>Horn Type</td><td>Berserkers Summoned</td><td>Requirement</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<tr><td>01-40</td><td>Silver</td><td>2d4 + 2</td><td>None</td></tr>
						<tr><td>41-75</td><td>Brass</td><td>3d4 + 3</td><td>Proficiency with all simple weapons</td></tr>
						<tr><td>76-90</td><td>Bronze</td><td>4d4 + 4</td><td>Proficiency with all medium armor</td></tr>
						<tr><td>91-00</td><td>Iron</td><td>5d4 + 5</td><td>Proficiency with all martial weapons</td></tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
				<p>If you blow the horn without meeting its requirement, the summoned berserkers attack you. If you meet the requirement, they are friendly to you and your companions and follow your commands.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">summon</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>


		<element name="Horseshoes of Speed" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HORSESHOES_OF_SPEED">
			<description>
				<p>These iron horseshoes come in a set of four. While all four shoes are affixed to the hooves of a horse or similar creature, they increase the creature's walking speed by 30 feet.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">mount</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--I-->
		<element name="Instrument of the Bard, Canaith Mandolin" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_INSTRUMENT_OF_THE_BARDS_CANAITH_MANDOLIN">
			<description>
				<p>An instrument of the bards is an exquisite example of it kind, superior to an ordinary instrument in every way. Seven types of these instruments exist, each named after a legendary bard college. The following table lists the spells common to all instruments, as well as the spells specific to each one and its rarity. A creature that attempts to play the instrument without being attuned to it must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or take 2d4 psychic damage.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can use an action to play the instrument and cast one of its spells. Once the instrument has been used to cast a spell, it can't be used to cast that spell again until the next dawn. The spells use your spellcasting ability and spell save DC.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can play the instrument while casting a spell that causes any of its targets to be charmed on a failed saving throw, thereby imposing disadvantage on the save. This effect applies only if the spell has a somatic or a material component.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Instrument</td><td>Rarity</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>All</td><td>-</td><td>Fly, invisibility, levitate, protection from evil and good, plus the spells listed for the particular instrument</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Anstruth harp</td><td>Very rare</td><td>Control weather, cure wounds (5th level), wall of thorns</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Canaith mandolin</td><td>Rare</td><td>Cure wounds (3rd level) , dispel magic, protection from energy (lightning only)</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Cli lyre</td><td>Rare</td><td>Stone shape, wall of fire, wind wall</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Doss lute</td><td>Uncommon</td><td>Animal friendship, protection from energy (fire only) , protection from poison</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Fochlucan</td><td>Uncommon</td><td>Entangle, faerie fire, shillelagh, bandore speak with animals</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Mac-Fuirmidh cittern</td><td>Uncommon</td><td>Barkskin, cure wounds, fog cloud</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Ollamh harp</td><td>Legendary</td><td>Confusion, control weather, fire storm</td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">bard</set>
				<set name="category">Musical Instruments</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="slot">onehand</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Instrument of the Bard, Cli Lyre" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_INSTRUMENT_OF_THE_BARDS_CLI_LYRE">
			<description>
				<p>An instrument of the bards is an exquisite example of it kind, superior to an ordinary instrument in every way. Seven types of these instruments exist, each named after a legendary bard college. The following table lists the spells common to all instruments, as well as the spells specific to each one and its rarity. A creature that attempts to play the instrument without being attuned to it must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or take 2d4 psychic damage.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can use an action to play the instrument and cast one of its spells. Once the instrument has been used to cast a spell, it can't be used to cast that spell again until the next dawn. The spells use your spellcasting ability and spell save DC.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can play the instrument while casting a spell that causes any of its targets to be charmed on a failed saving throw, thereby imposing disadvantage on the save. This effect applies only if the spell has a somatic or a material component.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Instrument</td><td>Rarity</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>All</td><td>-</td><td>Fly, invisibility, levitate, protection from evil and good, plus the spells listed for the particular instrument</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Anstruth harp</td><td>Very rare</td><td>Control weather, cure wounds (5th level), wall of thorns</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Canaith mandolin</td><td>Rare</td><td>Cure wounds (3rd level) , dispel magic, protection from energy (lightning only)</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Cli lyre</td><td>Rare</td><td>Stone shape, wall of fire, wind wall</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Doss lute</td><td>Uncommon</td><td>Animal friendship, protection from energy (fire only) , protection from poison</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Fochlucan</td><td>Uncommon</td><td>Entangle, faerie fire, shillelagh, bandore speak with animals</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Mac-Fuirmidh cittern</td><td>Uncommon</td><td>Barkskin, cure wounds, fog cloud</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Ollamh harp</td><td>Legendary</td><td>Confusion, control weather, fire storm</td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">bard</set>
				<set name="category">Musical Instruments</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="slot">onehand</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Ioun Stone, Awareness" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_IOUN_STONE_AWARENESS">
			<description>
				<p>You can't be surprised while this dark blue rhomboid orbits your head.</p>

				<p>An <em>Ioun stone</em> is named after Ioun, a god of knowledge and prophecy revered on some worlds. Many types of <em>Ioun stone</em> exist, each type a distinct combination of shape and color.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you use an action to toss one of these stones into the air, the stone orbits your head at a distance of 1d3 feet and confers a benefit to you. Thereafter, another creature must use an action to grasp or net the stone to separate it from you, either by making a successful attack roll against AC 24 or a successful DC 24 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. You can use an action to seize and stow the stone, ending its effect.</p>
				<p class="indent">A stone has AC 24, 10 hit points, and resistance to all damage. It is considered to be an object that is being worn while it orbits your head.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">surprised</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Ioun Stone, Protection" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_IOUN_STONE_PROTECTION">
			<description>
				<p>You gain a +1 bonus to AC while this dusty rose prism orbits your head.</p>

				<p>An <em>Ioun stone</em> is named after Ioun, a god of knowledge and prophecy revered on some worlds. Many types of <em>Ioun stone</em> exist, each type a distinct combination of shape and color.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you use an action to toss one of these stones into the air, the stone orbits your head at a distance of 1d3 feet and confers a benefit to you. Thereafter, another creature must use an action to grasp or net the stone to separate it from you, either by making a successful attack roll against AC 24 or a successful DC 24 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. You can use an action to seize and stow the stone, ending its effect.</p>
				<p class="indent">A stone has AC 24, 10 hit points, and resistance to all damage. It is considered to be an object that is being worn while it orbits your head.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">armor</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Ioun Stone, Reserve" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_IOUN_STONE_RESERVE">
			<description>
				<p>This vibrant purple prism stores spells cast into it, holding them until you use them. The stone can store up to 3 levels worth of spells at a time. When found, it contains 1d4 - 1 levels of stored spells chosen by the GM.</p>
				<p class="indent">Any creature can cast a spell of 1st through 3rd level into the stone by touching it as the spell is cast. The spell has no effect, other than to be stored in the stone. If the stone can't hold the spell, the spell is expended without effect. The level of the slot used to cast the spell determines how much space it uses.</p>
				<p class="indent">While this stone orbits your head, you can cast any spell stored in it. The spell uses the slot level, spell save DC, spell attack bonus, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell. The spell cast from the stone is no longer stored in it, freeing up space.</p>

				<p>An <em>Ioun stone</em> is named after Ioun, a god of knowledge and prophecy revered on some worlds. Many types of <em>Ioun stone</em> exist, each type a distinct combination of shape and color.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you use an action to toss one of these stones into the air, the stone orbits your head at a distance of 1d3 feet and confers a benefit to you. Thereafter, another creature must use an action to grasp or net the stone to separate it from you, either by making a successful attack roll against AC 24 or a successful DC 24 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. You can use an action to seize and stow the stone, ending its effect.</p>
				<p class="indent">A stone has AC 24, 10 hit points, and resistance to all damage. It is considered to be an object that is being worn while it orbits your head.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Ioun Stone, Sustenance" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_IOUN_STONE_SUSTENANCE">
			<description>
				<p>You don't need to eat or drink while this clear spindle orbits your head.</p>

				<p>An <em>Ioun stone</em> is named after Ioun, a god of knowledge and prophecy revered on some worlds. Many types of <em>Ioun stone</em> exist, each type a distinct combination of shape and color.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you use an action to toss one of these stones into the air, the stone orbits your head at a distance of 1d3 feet and confers a benefit to you. Thereafter, another creature must use an action to grasp or net the stone to separate it from you, either by making a successful attack roll against AC 24 or a successful DC 24 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. You can use an action to seize and stow the stone, ending its effect.</p>
				<p class="indent">A stone has AC 24, 10 hit points, and resistance to all damage. It is considered to be an object that is being worn while it orbits your head.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Íta Mâl" type="Item" source="Mraz-Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_ITEM_ITA_MAL">
			<description>
				<p>A creature subjected to this poison must make a DC 15 (+1 per failed save), Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, Upon lifting the vial to the characters nose and inhaling deeply, the user will be filled with an immense sense of power and benefit from the below effects for 8 hour:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>Advantage on Str Ability Checks.</li>
					<li>Bonus Action to use Dash.</li>
					<li>Your size counts as one larger for weight limits.</li>
					<li>In combat you can take one extra action per battle.</li>
				</ul>
				<p></p>
				<div class="reference">
					<div element="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_POISON_INHALED" />
				</div>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">poison,ihnale</set>
				<set name="category">Poison</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">125</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0.02">1/50 lb.</set>
				<set name="stackable">true</set>
			</setters>
			<sheet alt="Íta Mâl (Inhaled)" />		
		</element>
		<element name="Iron Bands of Bilarro" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_IRON_BANDS_OF_BILARRO">
			<description>
				<p>This rusty iron sphere measures 3 inches in diameter and weighs 1 pound.  You can use an action to speak the command word and throw the sphere at a Huge or smaller creature you can see within 60 feet of you. As the sphere moves through the air, it opens into a tangle of metal bands.</p>
				<p class="indent">Make a ranged attack roll with an attack bonus equal to your Dexterity modifier plus your proficiency bonus. On a hit, the target is restrained until you take a bonus action to speak the command word again to release it. Doing so, or missing with the attack, causes the bands to contract and become a sphere once more.</p>
				<p class="indent">A creature, including the one restrained, can use an action to make a DC 20 Strength check to break the iron bands. On a success, the item is destroyed, and the restrained creature is freed. If the check fails, any further attempts made by that creature automatically fail until 24 hours have elapsed.</p>
				<p class="indent">Once the bands are used, they can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--J-->
	<!--K-->
	<!--L-->
	<!--M-->
		<element name="Mantle of Spell Resistance" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_MANTLE_OF_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
			<description>
				<p>You have advantage on saving throws against spells while you wear this cloak.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">saving throw</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--N-->
		<element name="Necklace of Fireballs" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_NECKLACE_OF_FIREBALLS">
			<description>
				<p>This necklace has 1d6 + 3 beads hanging from it. You can use an action to detach a bead and throw it up to 60 feet away. When it reaches the end of its trajectory, the bead detonates as a 3rd level <em>fireball</em> spell (save DC 15).</p>
				<p class="indent">You can hurl multiple beads, or even the whole necklace, as one action. When you do so, increase the level of the <em>fireball</em> by 1 for each bead beyond the first.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">neck</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Necklace of Prayer Beads" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_NECKLACE_OF_PRAYER_BEADS">
			<description>
				<p>This necklace has 1d4 + 2 magic beads made from aquamarine, black pearl, or topaz. It also has many nonmagical beads made from stones such as amber, bloodstone, citrine, coral, jade, pearl, or quartz. If a magic bead is removed from the necklace, that bead loses its magic.</p>
				<p class="indent">Six types of magic beads exist. The GM decides the type of each bead on the necklace or determines it randomly. A necklace can have more than one bead of the same type. To use one, you must be wearing the necklace. Each bead contains a spell that you can cast from it as a bonus action (using your spell save DC if a save is necessary). Once a magic bead's spell is cast, that bead can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>d20</td><td>Bead of ...</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<tr><td>1-6</td><td>Blessing</td><td><em>Bless</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7-12</td><td>Curing</td><td><em>Cure wounds</em> (2nd level) or <em>lesser restoration</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>13-16</td><td>Favor</td><td><em>Greater restoration</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>17-18</td><td>Smiting</td><td><em>Branding smite</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>19</td><td>Summons</td><td><em>Planar ally</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>20</td><td>Wind walking</td><td><em>Wind walk</em></td></tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">cleric, druid, or paladin</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">neck</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric, druid, or paladin">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Periapt of Proof Against Poison" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_PERIAPT_OF_PROOF_AGAINST_POISON">
			<description>
				<p>This delicate silver chain has a brilliant-cut black gem pendant. While you wear it, poisons have no effect on you. You are immune to the poisoned condition and have immunity to poison damage.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">resistance, immunity</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">neck</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Portable Hole" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_PORTABLE_HOLE">
			<description>
				<p>This fine black cloth, soft as silk, is folded up to the dimensions of a handkerchief. It unfolds into a circular sheet 6 feet in diameter.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can use an action to unfold a <em>portable hole</em> and place it on or against a solid surface, whereupon the <em>portable hole</em> creates an extradimensional hole 10 feet deep. The cylindrical space within the hole exists on a different plane, so it can't be used to create open passages. Any creature inside an open <em>portable hole</em> can exit the hole by climbing out of it.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can use an action to close a <em>portable hole</em> by taking hold of the edges of the cloth and folding it up. Folding the cloth closes the hole, and any creatures or objects within remain in the extradimensional space. No matter what's in it, the hole weighs next to nothing.</p>
				<p class="indent">If the hole is folded up, a creature within the hole's extradimensional space can use an action to make a DC 10 Strength check. On a successful check, the creature forces its way out and appears within 5 feet of the <em>portable hole</em> or the creature carrying it. A breathing creature within a closed <em>portable hole</em> can survive for up to 10 minutes, after which time it begins to suffocate.</p>
				<p class="indent">Placing a <em>portable hole</em> inside an extradimensional space created by a <em>bag of holding</em>, <em>handy haversack</em>, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it and deposited in a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">extradimensional</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--O-->
	<!--P-->
	<!--Q-->
		<element name="Quaal’s Feather Token" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_QUAALS_FEATHER_TOKEN">
			<description>
				<p>This tiny object looks like a feather. Different types of feather tokens exist, each with a different single-use effect. The GM chooses the kind of token or determines it randomly.</p>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>d100</td><td>Feather Token</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<tr><td>01-20</td><td>Anchor</td></tr>
						<tr><td>21-35</td><td>Bird</td></tr>
						<tr><td>36-50</td><td>Fan</td></tr>
						<tr><td>51-65</td><td>Swan boat</td></tr>
						<tr><td>66-90</td><td>Tree</td></tr>
						<tr><td>91-00</td><td>Whip</td></tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Anchor.</em></strong> You can use an action to touch the token to a boat or ship. For the next 24 hours, the vessel can't be moved by any means. Touching the token to the vessel again ends the effect. When the effect ends, the token disappears.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bird.</em></strong> You can use an action to toss the token 5 feet into the air. The token disappears and an enormous, multicolored bird takes its place.  The bird has the statistics of a roc, but it obeys your simple commands and can't attack. It can carry up to 500 pounds while flying at its maximum speed (16 miles an hour for a maximum of 144 miles per day, with a one-hour rest for every 3 hours of flying), or 1,000 pounds at half that speed. The bird disappears after flying its maximum distance for a day or if it drops to 0 hit points. You can dismiss the bird as an action.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Fan.</em></strong> If you are on a boat or ship, you can use an action to toss the token up to 10 feet in the air. The token disappears, and a giant flapping fan takes its place. The fan floats and creates a wind strong enough to fill the sails of one ship, increasing its speed by 5 miles per hour for 8 hours. You can dismiss the fan as an action.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Swan Boat.</em></strong> You can use an action to touch the token to a body of water at least 60 feet in diameter. The token disappears, and a 50-foot-long, 20-foot- wide boat shaped like a swan takes its place. The boat is self-propelled and moves across water at a speed of 6 miles per hour. You can use an action while on the boat to command it to move or to turn up to 90 degrees. The boat can carry up to thirty-two Medium or smaller creatures. A Large creature counts as four Medium creatures, while a Huge creature counts as nine. The boat remains for 24 hours and then disappears. You can dismiss the boat as an action.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Tree.</em></strong> You must be outdoors to use this token. You can use an action to touch it to an unoccupied space on the ground. The token disappears, and in its place a nonmagical oak tree springs into existence. The tree is 60 feet tall and has a 5-foot-diameter trunk, and its branches at the top spread out in a 20-foot radius.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Whip.</em></strong> You can use an action to throw the token to a point within 10 feet of you. The token disappears, and a floating whip takes its place. You can then use a bonus action to make a melee spell attack against a creature within 10 feet of the whip, with an attack bonus of +9. On a hit, the target takes 1d6+5 force damage.</p>
				<p>As a bonus action on your turn, you can direct the whip to fly up to 20 feet and repeat the attack against a creature within 10 feet of it. The whip disappears after 1 hour, when you use an action to dismiss it, or when you are incapacitated or die.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"></set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--R-->
		<element name="Robe of Eyes" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_ROBE_OF_EYES">
			<description>
				<p>This robe is adorned with eyelike patterns. While you wear the robe, you gain the following benefits:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>The robe lets you see in all directions, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</li>
					<li>You have darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</li>
					<li>You can see invisible creatures and objects, as well as see into the Ethereal Plane, out to a range of 120 feet.</li>
				</ul>
				<p class="indent">The eyes on the robe can't be closed or averted. Although you can close or avert your own eyes, you are never considered to be doing so while wearing this robe.</p>
				<p class="indent">A <em>light</em> spell cast on the robe or a <em>daylight</em> spell cast within 5 feet of the robe causes you to be blinded for 1 minute. At the end of each of your turns, you can make a Constitution saving throw (DC 11 for <em>light</em> or DC 15 for <em>daylight</em>), ending the blindness on a success.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">darkvision, perception, invisible</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Rope of Entanglement" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_ROPE_OF_ENTANGLEMENT">
			<description>
				<p>This rope is 30 feet long and weighs 3 pounds. If you hold one end of the rope and use an action to speak its command word, the other end darts forward to entangle a creature you can see within 20 feet of you. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or become restrained.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can release the creature by using a bonus action to speak a second command word. A target restrained by the rope can use an action to make a DC 15 Strength or Dexterity check (target's choice). On a success, the creature is no longer restrained by the rope.</p>
				<p class="indent">The rope has AC 20 and 20 hit points. It regains 1 hit point every 5 minutes as long as it has at least 1 hit point. If the rope drops to 0 hit points, it is destroyed.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--S-->
		<element name="Stone of Controlling Earth Elementals" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_STONE_OF_CONTROLLING_EARTH_ELEMENTALS">
			<description>
				<p>If the stone is touching the ground, you can use an action to speak its command word and summon an earth elemental, as if you had cast the <em>conjure elemental</em> spell. The stone can't be used this way again until the next dawn. The stone weighs 5 pounds.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">summon</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--T-->
	<!--U-->
	<!--V-->
		<element name="Ventilating Lungs" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_VENTILATING_LUNGS">
			<description>
				<p>These metallic nodules were created in response to the poisonous gases used on the battlefields of the Last War. When you attune to these lungs, they replace the lungs in your chest, which disappear. The lungs allow you to breathe normally, even in an antimagic field, and their breathing function can’t be suppressed by magic.</p>
				<p class="indent">Outside an antimagic field or any other effect that suppresses magic, these lungs allow you to breathe normally in any environment (including a vacuum), and you have advantage on saving throws against harmful gases such as those created by a cloudkill spell, a stinking cloud spell, inhaled poisons, and gaseous breath weapons .</p>
				<p class="indent">As an action, you can use these lungs to exhale a gust of wind, as if you had cast the gust of wind spell (spell save DC 15) with no components. This property of the lungs can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
				<p class="indent">If your attunement to the lungs ends, your original lungs reappear.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--W-->
		<element name="Wings of Flying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_WINGS_OF_FLYING">
			<description>
				<p>While wearing this cloak, you can use an action to speak its command word. This turns the cloak into a pair of bat wings or bird wings on your back for 1 hour or until you repeat the command word as an action. The wings give you a flying speed of 60 feet. When they disappear, you can't use them again for 1d12 hours.</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords">cloak, fly</set>
				<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
				<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
				<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
				<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
				<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
				<set name="attunement">true</set>
				<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	<!--X-->
	<!--Y-->
	<!--Z-->
</elements>
