<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="harborfolk.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Rinxin/elements/master/core/backgrounds/harborfolk.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>	
		
	<element name="Harborfolk" type="Background" source="Adventurers League: Elemental Evil" id="ID_WOTC_ALEE_BACKGROUND_HARBORFOLK">
		<description>
			<p>You are one of the hundreds of small-time fishermen and women who haul the bounty of Mulmaster's freshwater harbor to the city's markets each morning. You have spent countless days rowing in the waters in and around Mulmaster and know them and the other fisherfolk, dockworkers, and port inhabitants better than anyone. Though you have left that life behind, you still visit once in a while.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Athletics, Sleight of Hand</li>
				<li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One type of gaming set, vehicles (water)</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> Fishing tackle, dice set, playing card set, or Three Dragon Ante set, a set of common clothes, rowboat, and a belt containing 5 gp</li>
				<li><strong>Lifestyle:</strong> Poor</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ALEE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HARBORFOLK" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Athletics, Sleight of Hand, Gaming Set, Vehicles (Water)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Gaming Set, Harborfolk" supports="Gaming Set" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_WATER" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ALEE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HARBORFOLK" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
				<item id="1">I am curious. I want to know why things are the way they are and why people do the things that they do.</item>
				<item id="2">I can't sing, but that never stops me from doing it, loudly. Everyone loves a good sea chanty!</item>
				<item id="3">I think the High Blade is doing a terrific job, don't you?</item>
				<item id="4">I'm very excited that the House Built on Gold is being restored. I am a zealous worshipper of Waukeen.</item>
				<item id="5">I am quite superstitious. I see portents in everyday occurances.</item>
				<item id="6">I resent the rich and enjoy thwarting their plans and spoiling their fun in small ways.</item>
				<item id="7">I have a sea story to fit every occasion.</item>
				<item id="8">I'm a fisher, but I secretly detest eating fish. I will do anything to avoid it.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Calm: For all things, there is a tide. I set sail when it is right, and mend my nets when it is not. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Windblown: I go where the winds blow. No man or woman tells me where or when to sail. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="3">Aspiring: I will gain the favor of a Zor or Zora patron, maybe even one of the Blades! (Any)</item>
				<item id="4">Salty: I want people to look to me as an expert on plying Mulmaster Harbor. (Any)</item>
				<item id="5">Selfless: We are all children of the sea. I help everyone in peril afloat and ashore. (Good)</item>
				<item id="6">Let them Drown: I refuse to risk my hide to help others. They wouldn't help me if roles were reversed. (Evil)</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Bond">
				<item id="1">I once lost everything but my rowboat. I'll do anything to protect it.</item>
				<item id="2">My brother was in the Soldiery, but he was killed. I really look up to the men and women who serve.</item>
				<item id="3">The Cloaks killed my friend for spellcasting. I'll get them back somehow, someday.</item>
				<item id="4">The High House of Hurting helped me when I was hurt and asked nothing in return. I owe them my life.</item>
				<item id="5">I was robbed in the Zhent ghetto once. It will not happen again.</item>
				<item id="6">I would do anything to protect the other harborfolk. They are my family.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Flaw">
				<item id="1">I drink too much, which causes me to miss the tide.</item>
				<item id="2">I killed a drunk member of the City Watch in a brawl. I am terrified that they might find out.</item>
				<item id="3">I oversell myself and make promises I can't keep when I want to impress someone.</item>
				<item id="4">Book learning is a waste of time. I have no patience for people who don't speak from experience.</item>
				<item id="5">I almost always cheat. I can't help myself.</item>
				<item id="6">I am a secret informant for the Hawks. I send them reports about everything I see and hear, even what my friends and allies are up to.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Harborfolk" type="Background Feature" source="Adventurers League: Elemental Evil" id="ID_WOTC_ALEE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HARBORFOLK">
		<description>
			<p>You grew up on the docks and waters of Mulmaster Harbor. The harborfolk remember you and still treat you as one of them. They welcome you and your companions. While they might charge you for it, they'll always offer what food and shelter they have; they'll even hide you if the City Watch is after you (but not if the Hawks are).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Harborfolk" />
	</element>
</elements>