<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Deep Magic 16: Time Magic</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="time-lost-traveler.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Rinxin/elements/master/core/backgrounds/time-lost-traveler.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Time-Lost Traveler" type="Background" source="Deep Magic 16: Time Magic" id="ID_KBP_DMTM_BACKGROUND_TIME_LOST_TRAVELER">
		<description>
			<p>You come from the past. Whether you just escaped from magical stasis, were resurrected by a time storm in the Wastes, were sent forward in time by lost gods, or were the victim of some other magical occurrence, you’ve found yourself hundreds of years or more from your time of origin. The world has changed in the interim, but you have unrivaled knowledge about the cultures and relics of past times.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> History, Survival</li>
				<li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Cartographer’s tools or navigator’s tools </li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of the following—Ankeshelian, Illyrian, Morphoi, or Vos’Ghaen</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A leather case containing a map of a now-ancient city, a bullseye lantern, a set of traveler’s clothes, a trinket brought from your time, and a pouch containing 25 gp in antique coins.</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_KBP_DMTM_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ANACHRONISTIC_KNOWLEDGE" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>Travelers who become lost in time are tenacious survivors. They may feel that their time was superior, or may be pleasantly surprised by the changes that have occurred in the world. In either case, they make their way in the new world to the best of their ability.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">History, Survival, Cartographer’s Tools / Navigator’s Tools, Ankeshelian / Illyrian / Morphoi / Vos’Ghaen</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Time-Lost Traveler" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CARTOGRAPHERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_NAVIGATORS_TOOLS" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language, Time-Lost Traveler" supports="Time Lost Traveler" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_KBP_DMTM_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ANACHRONISTIC_KNOWLEDGE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
				<item id="1">I don’t speak much. No one must learn where or when I came from.</item>
				<item id="2">I am fascinated by clockwork, and I collect examples whenever possible.</item>
				<item id="3">I try to find out about the cultures of everyone I meet.</item>
				<item id="4">I make sure to always carry traveling supplies with me.</item>
				<item id="5">I make sure to live life to the fullest, in the here and now.</item>
				<item id="6">I am often struck by the knowledge that the people and places I knew are gone.</item>
				<item id="7">I pretend great naivete or ignorance for my own reasons.</item>
				<item id="8">I am far happier in ancient ruins than I am in other places.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Aspiration. I know that I was sent here for a reason. (Any)</item>
				<item id="2">Determination. I must find a way to return to my time. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="3">Protection. I have seen the horrors of history, and I will ensure they never happen again. (Good)</item>
				<item id="4">Greed. I know where the treasures were buried. Finders keepers. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="5">Freedom. I am no longer bound by the moral constraints of my original time. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="6">Necessity. I know that time must not be tampered with. (Lawful)</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Bond">
				<item id="1">I had a family. I need to find out what happened to my descendants.</item>
				<item id="2">Something has gone wrong with the flow of time, and I must redress this problem.</item>
				<item id="3">The city I came from has fallen from great heights. I can restore its prominence.</item>
				<item id="4">I must raise my fame and fortune to prove that I belong in this time.</item>
				<item id="5">I protect ancient sites from those who would seek to plunder their riches.</item>
				<item id="6">Someone else was also sent through time when I was. I need to find that person.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Flaw">
				<item id="1">I believe earlier people were superior. I constantly complain about modern values.</item>
				<item id="2">I let everyone know that I was part of every significant historical event, somehow.</item>
				<item id="3">I become enraged when anyone questions my version of history.</item>
				<item id="4">I judge other races harshly based on my time’s perception of them.</item>
				<item id="5">I will not make friends. They can be lost in an instant.</item>
				<item id="6">I take a very long time when I search or study historical sites.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Anachronistic Knowledge" type="Background Feature" source="Deep Magic 16: Time Magic" id="ID_KBP_DMTM_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ANACHRONISTIC_KNOWLEDGE">
		<description>
			<p>When you enter a ruin or dungeon, you can correctly ascertain its original purpose and determine its builders, whether those were dwarves, elves, humans, or some other race. You apply double your proficiency bonus on History checks when the check is related to knowledge from ancient times. You either lived in those times or they were recent history to you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Anachronistic Knowledge">
			<description>When you enter a ruin or dungeon, you can correctly ascertain its original purpose and determine its builders, whether those were dwarves, elves, humans, or some other race. You apply double your proficiency bonus on History checks when the check is related to knowledge from ancient times. You either lived in those times or they were recent history to you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>